自去年後進入公司後 我的妻子總是鼓勵我
You know, after last year's corporate, my wife was always encouraging me.
她說，你幹得很出色 你在公司幹得很出色
You know, she said: you did fine, you did fine in the corporate.
我有些緊張 這小麥克風...哈羅，對不起
I was a bit nervous. This little guy... hello. Sorry.
這樣很好，是嗎？ 很好的背景，有人在那裡
That's nice, eh? Nice background with the people there...
- 我們正在...我必須這樣看？ - 直看著鏡頭就好
We are here at the... must I look..? -Just look straight at the lens.
我們現在在MNU（多國聯）總部
We are here at the... MNU head office,
外星人事務部 我是維庫斯·范德默爾
Wikus Van De Merwe Department of Alien Affairs. My name is Wikus Van De Merwe.
在我身後，你會看到其他 外星人事務處的工作人員
And behind me you can see the Alien Affairs' workers.
我們這個部門的工作是
And what we do here at this department is...
我們試圖與大蝦溝通交流
we try to engage with the Prawn
為了MNU和人類的利益
on behalf of MNU and on behalf of humans.
讓所有人都感到意外的是 太空船並沒有停在
To everyone's surprise, the ship didn't come to a stop
曼哈頓，華盛頓，抑或芝加哥
over Manhattan or Washington or Chicago,
反而直接停在了約翰內斯堡上空
but instead it costed to a halt directly over the city of Johannesburg.
船門在三個月內都沒有打開 它就懸浮在那裡，沒人能夠進去
The doors didn't open for 3 months. It just hovered there. Nobody could get in.
在深思熟慮之後，他們終於決定
And they eventually decided, after much deliberation,
最好的方法是切割飛船 破門而入
that the best thing to do would be to physically cut their way in.
我們即將進行第一次接觸
We were on the verge of first contact.
整個世界都在注視著
The whole world was watching.
期待著，或許是…
Expecting, I don't know...
音樂伴著強光閃耀從天而降
...music from heaven and bright shining lights.
哦，天呀
Oh my God!
這生物非常營養不良
The creatures were extremely malnourished,
他們非常不健康 看起來精神恍惚
they were very unhealthy, they seemed to be aimless.
那時，我們承受著來自世界各地的壓力
There was a lot of international pressure on us at the time.
整個世界都在看著約翰內斯堡
The entire world was looking at Johannesburg,
因此，我們必須做正確的事情
so we had to do the right thing.
隨後政府成立了一個援救小組開始
The government then established an aid group that started to
將這些外星人運送到 船下方的建立的臨時營地裡
ferry the aliens to a temporary camp set up just beneath the ship.
我們並沒有明確的計劃 他們有數百萬人
We didn't have a plan. There was a million of them.
因此，臨時的收容所就成為了隔離區
So, what was a temporary holding zone soon became fenced,
並開始實施軍事化管理 而在之前，這是一個貧民窟
became militarized. And before we knew it, it was a slum.
但事實是，沒人真正知道 這究竟是什麼地方
But the truth is, nobody really knew what this place was.
在第九區有很多不為人知的秘密
There's a lot of secrets in District 9.
片名：《第九區》
起初，大家的注意力都集中在
At first, a lot of attention was given to...
給予外星人一個適當的地位和保護
giving the aliens a proper status and protection.
為了維持那些外星人生活 他們花了大量的錢
They're spending so much money to keep them here.
而這些錢本可以花在其它地方
When they could be spending it on other things, but...
但至少這把外星人和我們分開了
...at least they're keeping them separate from us.
我想每個人都應該實際點 這些外星人將不可能回到他們原來的星球
l want to be realistic with everyone. The aliens will not be able to go home.
外星人會在這裡長留下來
The aliens are here to stay.
對於這件事，人們有各種解釋
There were literally thousands of different theories
至於船為什麼無法操作 只能推測是
as to why the ship seemed inoperable, and what was speculated was that
指揮艙已經和主船分離了
the command module had detached itself from the main ship,
然後，又莫名其妙地失蹤了
and then somehow mysteriously became lost.
它是自己墮落的還是按照預定程序？ 我不知道
Did it fall by itself or was it programmed? I don't know.
認真檢查影像鏡頭
Examination of the old video footage
可以清楚地發現有一小塊東西 從船上掉落下來
shows very clearly that a piece falls from the ship.
我們搜索它 我們到處搜索它
We look for it. We look everywhere.
這一小塊墮落物引發了流血衝突
This piece that's falling caused us bloody problems.
發現了很多隱藏的武器
More energy weapon caches found.
特種部隊突襲了第九區
The Special task force conducted raids in District 9.
有武器的地方就有犯罪 緊張狀況不斷上升，上升
Where there's a weapon, there's crime. Tensions rose, and rose.
人們變得越來越不滿 並最終引發了騷亂
People became more and more fed up, and eventually the rioting started.
Tembisa的居民為了把外星人 從他們的小鎮上趕走
Residents in Tembisa rioted for the third consecutive night
連續暴動了三個晚上
in an attempt to remove all the aliens from their township.
我想他們一定要修好那艘船 他們必須離開
I think they must fix that ship and they must go.
病毒，精心挑選一種病毒 把它釋放到外星人附近
A virus, a selective virus. Release it near the aliens.
他們必須離開 不管去哪，儘管走開
They must just go. I don't know where, just go.
如果他們是來自其它 我們能理解的國家的話
If they was from another country we might understand.
但他們甚至都不是地球上的
But they are not even from this planet.
政府已實施全國宵禁
The government have enforced a nationwide curfew.
外星人，那些大蝦 他們奪走了我的妻子
The aliens, prawns, they take my wife away.
這個貶損的詞「大蝦」用來指那些外星人 很明顯，他暗指
The derogatory term Prawn is used for the alien, and obviously it implies
那些以食腐為生的低等動物
something that is a bottom feeder, that scavenges the leftovers.
我的意思是，你不能說 他們不像那種動物
I mean, you can't say they don't look like that.
他們看起來就是那個樣子，不是嗎？ 他們看起來的確像大蝦
That's what they look like, right? They look like prawns.
外星人搶走了數額不明的現金，一個旁觀者受傷了
The aliens made off with an undisclosed amount of cash. One bystander was hurt.
在外星人看來那些娛樂的事情
What for an alien might be seen as something recreational,
比如放火點燃汽車 讓火車出軌
setting fire to a truck, derailing a train,
對人們而言 這些都明顯是極端具有破壞性的行為
is for us obviously an extremely destructive act.
他們會搶走走你穿著的運動鞋
They can take the sneakers you are wearing off you.
他們會搶走你身上的一切 你的手機或者其它任何東西
They take whatever you have on you. Your cell phone or anything.
之後，他們會要了你的命
After that they kill you.
現在，20年後，公眾的壓力迫使政府
And now, after 20 years, public pressure had forced the government
將這些外星人移出約翰內斯堡
to shift the aliens out of Johannesburg.
他們受夠了，他們希望 第九區搬走
They had had enough and they wanted District 9 to be moved,
並受到更多警力更強的控制
and more intensively policed and controlled.
因此，要實施這個大規模的驅逐行動 政府借助於MNU的力量
So, to enforce this mass eviction, the government turned to MNU.
歡迎你們，謝謝你們的到來
Welcome all and thank you for coming.
請認真聽這個簡短的聲明
Please listen very closely to this briefing.
今天我們要開始一個非常複雜和棘手的行動
Today we start a very complex and delicate operation.
這是MNU所執行過的最大的行動
This is the largest operation that MNU has ever undertaken,
並且我們相信這次一定會執行地非常成功
and we believe that it is going to be undertaken successfully.
這次我們要將180萬大蝦
It is to move 1.8 million prawns
從他們現有的家第九區轉移到 位於約翰內斯堡200公里之外的
from their present home in District 9 to a safer and better location
一個更好更安全的場所
200 kilometers outside of Johannesburg City.
我們在那裡建造了一個更舒適的新環境 在哪裡，大蝦
We built a nice new facility where the prawn can go,
能夠過得相對舒適 它們可以呆在那裡
he can be comfortable, he can stay there...
大蝦遠離了約翰內斯堡和南非的居民
The people of Johannesburg and of South Africa are going to live
人們就可以過上快樂和安全的生活
happily and safely, knowing that that prawn is very far away.
UIO協議要求我們在驅逐前24小時
UIO protocol dictates that we give the aliens
給予外星人的驅逐通知
24 hours notice of our right to evict.
今天，你們將宣佈這一正式通知 讓外星人們簽訂I-27協議
Today, you will serve these notices getting the aliens to sign I-27 form.
MNU用來驅逐外星人的法律 實際上只是一個幌子
The legality that MNU is using to evict the aliens is simply a whitewash.
我將任命地區負責人來直接指揮
I'm going to appoint a field officer to take direct command.
維庫斯·范德默爾.
Wikus Van De Merwe.
人人都說維庫斯不是一個非常機靈的孩子
Everybody always said that Wikus was not a very smart boy,
但他是一個非凡的兒子 是我的維庫斯，正如...
but he was a wonderful son. That was my Wikus, just...
感覺這是人生的一大步 謝謝你，皮耶特...史密斯先生
Feels like life on the big stage. Thank you Piet... Mr Smith.
我得拋開我女兒嫁給維庫斯的事實
l had to put aside the fact that my daughter was married to Wikus.
那並沒有影響我提升他的決定
That didn't affect my decision to promote him.
這個升職幾乎和我結婚的日子一樣重大 嗯...當然還沒有結婚那麼重大
It's almost as big as my wedding day. You know... not as big.
維庫斯總給我親手製作很多東西
Wikus was always making me things.
他說這這些東西都情深意長
He said that way they just mean so much more.
有一天，他把這個紙缽留在了沙發上
He left this paper-mache bowl on the sofa one day
而我並沒有看到，我坐下了 並...把它壓扁了
and I didn't see it and I sat down, and I... kinda squashed it.
為了調查，他們把他的所有東西都帶走了
They took all his stuff away for the investigation, and...
而我向他們把東西全都要回來了
I made them bring it all back.
嘿，恭喜你，年輕人 謝謝，先生
Hey, congratulations, man! -Thanks, man.
你去P7 維庫斯！事情怎樣了？
Okay, you're gonna go to P7. -Wikus! -How is it going, man?
這麼辦吧，P9歸你 謝謝
Here's the shake. P9 for you. -Thanks.
我並不是說他做的是對的，但
I'm not saying what he did was right, but...
他選擇了那些給他的
he took the choices that were given to him.
- 這是特雷特 - 方德斯瓦, 特雷特.  -你好！
This is Trent. Fundiswa, Trent. -Hi.
方德斯瓦是我挑選來替補我的人
Fundiswa is the guy that I've selected to replace me.
- 今天他能做到嗎，啊？ - 我會做到的
If he can make it today, eh? -I'll make it.
我現在只想每個觀眾
I just want everyone watching this right now
能從中學到一些東西 你可能會認為
to learn from what has happened. -You would think...
這些事情只會發生在別人身上 不會發生在自己身上
things like this would happen to somebody else, not to me.
情況怎樣了？隊友 你有我的東西麼
How is it going, man? Long time, mate. Have you got my stuff?
喂，老闆！  -最近怎樣了？ 很好，老闆
Hey, boss! -How is it going? -I'm all right, boss.
好，好，這是方德斯瓦 他今天和我們一起訓練
Good, good, this is Fundiswa. He is training with us today.
我覺得我很討厭他的工作方式
I think I was disgusted with the way he worked.
總是給別人暗示 和范德默爾
There was always just a hint of something not quite kosher
- 不是很合適 - 沒人知道下一步他會幹啥
with mr Van De Merwe. -Nobody saw it coming at all.
我們都不知道他將要做什麼
None of us had any idea of what he was doing.
我想這是一個偉大的事情
l think it is a great thing to see that...
這次由非軍方人員管理
it's not the military guys in charge this time.
不是說庫布斯和他的那些牛仔不再重要了
Not to say that Koobus and his cowboys are not wanted.
你們這些傢伙一直很重要
You guys are always wanted.
現在你看到了吧 這些都是他手下
You see now, these are the cowboys.
他們先射擊，然後再回答問題
They shoot first, and then they answer the questions.
對不起，這是否超出了彈藥配給的數量
Sorry, is this above the allocated amount of ammunition?
因為我看到你裝了滿滿一袋子了
Because I see your pouches are full but...
我想也許你應該跟上校談
I think maybe you should speak to the colonel.
F.A.G過來說我們拿了太多的彈藥
F.A.G. over here says that we got too much ammunition.
不，我的意思是，庫布斯，是那個
No, all I'm saying, Koobus, is that, you know...
你應該找到一個讓他們工作更有效率的辦法
you should find ways of making you guys more efficient...
聽我說，你他媽的混小子！
Listen to me, you fuck!
趕緊讓他滾遠點
Get him outta my face.
無規矩不成方圓， 這世上我們都按照規矩行事
There are rules, we're all living by rules in this world.
我認為他那種做法是不可原諒的
Well, l don't think he can be forgiven for what he did,
- 因為這看起來就像是叛亂 - 我得開始出發了，Les
cause it's like a betrayal. -I've gotta get going, Les.
我想我們應該剪掉這個採訪，因為我們將...
I think we're gonna have to cut this interview, cause we're gonna go...
離第九區12公里
12 KILOMETERS FROM DISTRICT 9
帶上你的彈藥，走 我們走吧
Take your magazines, people. Come on, lets go.
大蝦並沒有財產領土的概念
The Prawn doesn't really understand the concept of ownership of property.
因此，我們去到那裡並說 聽著，這是我們的土地
So, we have to come there and say: listen, this is our land.
請，你會走開嗎？
Please, will you go?
自己一個人很難穿上防彈衣
It's difficult to put the vest on by yourself.
托馬斯，你能幫幫我麼？ 好的，頭
Thomas, can you help me? -All right, boss.
他們告訴我要把防彈衣穿在裡面
They told me I was gonna get the vest inside the Casper.
托馬斯，看看那邊還有防彈衣嗎？
Thomas, just look on the side if there's a vest there?
我只是擔心我的家人 別擔心防彈衣，一切都會很順利的
I'm just concerned about my family. -Don't worry about the vest, it'll be fine.
人權組織已經要求僱傭兵們在第九區
Rights groups have demanded that mercenaries should comply
應該遵從UYO規則
with all YO regulations in District 9.
我們正在第九區的入口出為你報道
We're coming to you from the entrance of District 9
今天，多國聯合部隊將開始重新安置
as today, Multi National United sets out to relocate
大約有180萬外星居民
approximately 1.8 million alien residents from their homes.
人權組織正在保持密切觀察
Human rights groups are keeping a watchful eye,
因為會有一些可疑的虐待行為發生
as many suspect abuses might occur.
我們正看到重裝齊備的私人安全部隊
We're seeing heavily armed private security forces
正被部署到第九區
being deployed into District 9.
並有大量的空中支援力量
Backed up by significant air support.
我們將進入一間一間小屋 並讓他們在表格上簽名
We'll go shack to shack and get them to sign the form.
第一個是EX247
First one EX 247.
我們看到車隊停下來了 行動馬上就要開始
We're seeing the convoy stop. The operation is about to begin.
集中精神
Just stay focused.
準備好了嗎，托馬斯？ 是的，準備好了
Are you ready, Thomas? -Yeah. -Okay.
那是一個信號嗎？ 是的，夥伴們
Is that a signal? Okay, fellows.
你和我們一起 祝你好運，
You stay behind us. Good luck, boy.
別起來，他要去哪？ 這是什麼？
Stay low! Where is he going? What is it?
很明顯，安全性非常高
It's clear that security is very high.
這只是全面驅逐行動的前奏
This is only the beginning of a total clamp down.
我們是MNU探員 請開門！開門！
This is MNU agents. Open the door please! -Open up!
喂！喂！喂...
Hello! Hello, hello...
我是MNU的維庫斯·范德默爾
This is Wikus Van De Merwe from MNU.
我們在這裡來發放驅逐通知的
We are here to serve you an eviction notice.
你只需要將在這裡簽字就好了 滾開
You just put your scrawl there. -Fuck off!
好的！托馬斯，慢著 我們已經取得了他的簽字
All right! Thomas, hold it! We've got his scrawl there.
因為它碰到它了 這也算
Because as he hit it, it counts as a scrawl.
每次我們進去時，我們之間
First time we come in, there will always be a little bit
都會出現一些緊張的對立
of tension happening between us and them.
嘿，你不能吃那個
Hey, you can't eat that, man!
大蝦喜歡吃橡膠 對他而言，這就像棉花糖一樣好吃
The prawn likes to eat the rubber. To him it's like a marshmallow.
別，別！警衛！ 別這樣對著著他
No, no! Guard! Don't confront him like that!
看到那了嗎？ 平靜點
Did you see that? Right in the roost. Stay calm!
這將成為一個問題 現在所有的大蝦都出來了
This is gonna be a problem cause now all prawns are coming out,
他們想弄清楚發生了什麼 停止！停止！
they wanna see what's going on. Stop it! Stop it!
把我的東西拿過來 看，他們都聚起來了
Bring my kit. See, everybody is gathering now.
別開槍，不然你將要把這裡變成一個戰場
Don't shoot or you're gonna turn it into a warzone!
- 那是什麼？那是催淚彈嗎？ - 不，這是貓糧
What is that? Is that a tear gas? -No, it's cat food.
這是貓糧 我只想引開他們的注意力
It is cat food. I just distract them.
其中一個襲擊了大蝦 他丟掉了他的手臂
One of them attacked the prawn and he's lost his arm.
不，這不是我的房子 我不住在那
No it's not my house. I don't live here.
那非常遺憾，你知道，這...
Well, that's a pity because, you know, this...
這是一種很好的貓糧 但當然，這並不是你的房子
This is a nice cat food, you know. But of course, it's not your house.
- 所以，我們要走了，把它給別人 - 是的！這是我的房子
So, we'll just have to go and give it to someone else. -Yes! It's my house!
我們要你在這裡簽名 現在你可以拿它了
We need you to sign here. Now you can take that...
好，停下
All right. Stop it!
這種生物變得對貓糧具有特殊的愛好
The creatures became incredibly obsessed with cat food.
一些像貓薄荷的東西，不過味道更重一點
Something about it, like catnip for cats. Only a lot more intense.
喂？MNU，我們正在發放驅逐通知
Hello? MNU. We are here to serve eviction notices.
什麼是驅逐？
What is eviction?
我們在地球上這個殖民地陷入困境
What we have stranded on Earth in this colony,
根本上是因為人們不會獨立思考
is basically the workers that are unable to think for themselves.
他們只會聽從命令 他們不掌握主動權
They will take commands, they have no initiative.
他們喪失了一切領導能力
They've lost all the apt of leadership
不管是什麼導致的 我們推斷這是疾病所致
through whatever cause. We presume illness.
我曾在尼日利亞復合區執行過安全維護
I'm holding steady over Nigerian compound area.
有貧民窟的地方就有犯罪 第九區也不例外
Where there's a slum, there's crime. And District 9 was no exception.
尼日利亞人詭計多端 其中一種就是貓糧騙術
The nigerians had various scams going. One of them was the cat food scam.
在那裡他們把貓糧價格以非常高的價格 出售給外星人
Where they sold cat food to the aliens for exorbitant prices.
你把錢放在這裡 然後你就可以拿著這些東西離開了
You put the money here first. You don't get anything until you pay.
你想幹什麼？ 我將把你的嘴打扁
What are you trying to do? I'll chop your balls off.
更別提種間賣淫了
Not to mention interspecies prostitution,
而且他們也給外星人出售武器
and they also dealt in alien weaponry.
有車輛被劫持了 有商舖被打劫了
You have a car hijacking, there's a chop shop there,
你可以看那 那裡有一輛車
you can see that, that's somebody's car in there.
第九區的尼日利亞人的頭是一個叫奧卑山卓的人
The nigerians in District 9 are headed by a man called Obesandjo.
他是約翰內斯堡黑社會組織中一個非常有權勢的人
He's a very powerful underground figure in Johannesburg.
你一定不想跟這些人打交道
You don't want to play with these boys.
他們會把你剁碎的
They will cut you into pieces.
那就是他們的頭 好的，沒問題
That's the boss there. OK, no problem.
別看他 會惹麻煩的
Don't look at him! This is gonna cause problems.
好，下一個是，766
All right, next. 766, all right.
MNU人員，請開門！
MNU agents. Open the door please!
喔！天呀！這是什麼？
Whoa! Jesus! What is it?
檢查另一面
Check the other side!
總部，我是維庫斯·范德默爾
Control, this is Wikus Van De Merwe.
在JV766，我需要一隻種群管制隊伍
I need a population control team at JV 766 immediately, please.
檢查另一邊，托馬斯 那裡有40到50個蛋
Check the other side, Thomas! There is 40 to 50 eggs in here.
這正常嗎？ 這真是一個讓人驚異的發現
Is this normal? -This is an amazing find.
我只能向你展示一二 它是如何工作的
l can just show you a little bit how it works.
基本上，一頭牛被懸掛在天花板上 就如你在這裡所看到的這樣
Basically, a cow is hung from the ceiling, you can see here.
它已經所剩無幾了，當然 因為所有的這些管道
Very little of it left, of course, because all these pipes
都在給這些小蝦蛋供送營養
supply the nutrition to the little prawn eggs.
你可以幹掉一個，我來告訴你 想要看嗎？ 不用了，謝謝
You can do one, I can show you, want to see? -No, I'm fine.
就這樣，好了 這傢伙再也沒有營養供應了
There we go. Okay, no more nutrition to the guy.
最後，我們把氧氣管也拔了
Then finally we take air back.
這些小傢伙可以睡會了
The little guy is gone to a nice little sleep now.
你把這些東西拔出來 把它拔出來
You pop him out, there we go. Pop him out here.
你可以留住這個。你可以把它當作 你這一次行動的紀念品
You can take that. You wanna keep it as a souvenir of your first abortion.
- 你可以想像你親手幹掉了一個了 - 謝謝，頭
You can feel like you did one of these here. -Thanks, boss.
好了，來了，夥計們 這是火槍
Okay, here it comes, guys. This is the snake.
如果我們一次只滅一個蛋
If we were going to abort each egg one at the time,
這會花上很長一段時間 所以，這樣更合理些
it'd take a very long time. So, this makes a lot of sense.
聽到了嗎？現在正傳來砰砰的聲音
You hear that? That's a popping sound that you're hearing.
聽起來就像爆米花
It's almost like a popcorn.
這些蛋就爆開了
What the egg does, it pops up.
這些留在那裡的小傢伙 就爆破開了
The little guy, what's left of him, pops out there.
所以，你們就聽到了砰砰的響聲
So that's the sound that you're hearing with the popping.
哥們，你不需要這個 只有女人才戴那玩意
You don't need that, man. Only sissies wear that.
在這裡喝得有些醉了？
Been drinking a little bit here, eh?
你在對這電視做什麼？這是什麼？
What are you doing with this television set, sir? What's this?
喂，對著鏡頭笑笑
Hey, smile for the cameras here.
那是第一天的發現 那是一個大發現
That's a first day find. -That's a big find.
看到沒？特雷特，看看這個 這裡到處都是武器
You see this? Trent, look at this! There's weapons all over here.
CK 5, 7572...
一些槍很小
Some of the guns are small
但你一旦被射中 後果也是不可設想的
but if it shoot you, it make a big mess.
MNU出於人道的目地要遷走外星人
MNU is trying to move the aliens for humanitarian reasons.
但真正的重點 就如一開始所呈現的那樣
But the real focus, just as it has been
焦點是武器
right from the beginning, is weapons.
MNU是世界上第二大武器製造商
MNU is the second largest weapons manufacturer in the world.
我們以為我們拿起外星人的激光槍
We assumed that we'd be able to pick up the alien laser gun
就能夠射擊 但事實上並非如此
and just be able to shoot, but it didn't work like that.
因為，我們發現 他們的技術實際上
Because, as we discovered, their technology is actually
整合了生物技術 要他們的DNA才能發動這些武器
engineered in a biological manner to interact exclusively with their DNA.
人類就無法使用 道理就是這樣簡單
It just doesn't work with humans. And it's as simple as that.
這畫畫的是一個大蝦，三個人類
This is basically a guy, and there's 3 humans here.
應該是在警告我們
Basically trying to make a warning, you know.
似乎正在說「三個人都被我干了 你們離我遠點」
He's saying "I kill 3 humans, watch out for me."
喂，別在自己的地盤上撒尿 退後，退後
Hey, don't urinate on your own bloody... get back, get back.
我是維庫斯，請求第一營護送
This is Wikus, requesting First Battalion escort, please.
你想和他們談 還是想和我談
You want to talk to them or you want to talk to me?
不，不是他們
No, not them!
好的，夥計們，太謝謝了 是的，我知道，他有把鏟刀
Okay, guys, thanks very much. Yeah I know, he had a spade.
看，我找到了
Look-I find some!
我告訴過你了...這是 人類的東西，毫無用處
I tell you before... this is human technology, it is useless.
只有我們的東西裡面才包含著流體
Only our technology contains the fluid.
這不是我們的東西？ 不，這只是垃圾
This is not our technology? -No, it's junk.
繼續尋找
Keep looking.
我發現了一些東西
I find something.
是的，這就是我們所需要的
Yes. This is what we need.
做得很棒，小傢伙
Good, little one.
趴下
Get down!
小心...等會...
Careful... wait...
...那邊
...there.
為什麼一定要那麼長的時間
Why must it take so long?
因為這相當困難...
Because it is very difficult...
...很多環節都可能出錯
...so much can go wrong.
二十年的努力了
Twenty years of work.
我們的計劃是不是已經準備好了？ 安靜...聽...
Our plan is ready now? -Quiet... listen...
...他們過來了
...they are coming.
你必須把這個藏起來 絕不能讓他們找到它
You must hide this. They must not find it.
去開門並保持友好
Answer the door and be polite.
不！你帶上它
No! You take it.
你看，這就是問題所在了 這就是團伙的標誌
You see, this is the problem. This is the gang sign.
你看到這沒？所以 看起來我們找到了
You see this? So again, looks like we have
越來越多的幫派成員
more and more gang members.
方德斯瓦，你先站在後面 你站在托馬斯後面
Fundiswa, you just stay back. You stay behind Thomas.
這裡到處是MNU的人 肯定會被發現的
This place is swarming with MNU. I will be searched.
我必須回到我孩子身邊 別惹他們生氣～禮貌點
I must get back to my son. Don't make them angry - be polite!
MNU探員，請開門
MNU agents, open the door please.
你好，我們想要你... 這裡沒人
Hello? We would like you to... -Nobody is here.
不能這樣 那完全不可接受
Okay, that's unexceptable. That is totally unexceptable!
滾出來！滾出來！ 你這只蠢蝦
Get out! Get out! You stupid prawn!
出來 來！走開，走開
-Get outside! -C'mon! Move! Move!
跪著 我進去看一看
On your knees! -I'm gonna have a look.
呆在這裡 這裡
Just stay there! Right there!
先生，我是來給你發放驅逐通知的
Sir, we have to serve you an eviction notice.
你不知道嗎？ 不知道
Do you understand it? -No.
這是一個典型的幫派集會的場所 我可以看出來
This is a classic kind of gangsta shack, I can tell you.
我們肯定能在這裡發現武器 小心你的頭，別碰到牛
We're gonna find weapons here. Watch your head, don't hit the cows.
檢查那些控制板 啊，你聽到了嗎
Just checking for panels. Ah, you hear that?
是的，裡面是空的
Yeah, it's hollow there.
看，看那
See? Look at that!
我還沒看過這樣的裝置 它看起來就像一個...
I haven't see this type of setup. It's almost like a...
化學實驗裝備
chemistry type of a set.
這裡一定有些什麼東西
It's gotta be something.
我不確定，這裡有一些標誌
l don't know, this has got the markings there of...
這毫無疑問是外星人留下的
...so it is definitely alien.
但這不是武器 但我不相信它
But it's not a weapon. But I don't trust it.
你沒事吧？ 維庫斯，你沒事吧？
Are you all right? Wikus, are you all right?
關了它，請關了它
Switch it off, please. Just turn it off.
你會把這一段剪掉吧，那段它朝我噴射的
Are you gonna cut that part out, Trent, where it sprays me?
是的，別擔心 記得把那段剪掉
-Yeah, don't worry. -You cut that.
我們剛在這裡發現了一個危險的東西
We just found a dangerous object here.
裡面有液體，而且我懷疑弄到人身上會引發傷害
It has a fuel in and I suspect it might leak onto people or cause damage.
所以我們把它裝在裡面，並帶回實驗室
So we just check that in and we take that down nicely to the lab.
這不是武器 但是很危險
It's not a weapon but it's dangerous.
我的直覺告訴我 他在這裡隱藏了一些武器
He's got weapons somewhere here, my sense is telling me that.
我們檢查另一邊 托馬斯！  —是的，先生
Lets check the other side here. Thomas! -Yes sir?
托馬斯，槍繼續對著他 -好的，收到
Thomas, keep the gun on him. -OK, I got it sir!
槍繼續對著他，托馬斯 這裡有個武器
Keep the gun on him, Thomas, there's weapons here!
哦，重大發現！ 重大發現，朋友們
Oh, this is Christmas! This is Christmas, my friends.
這我見過的最大的發現
This is the biggest find that I've ever seen.
總部，維庫斯·范德默爾
Control, come in. Wikus Van De Merwe,
請求第一營支援
requesting First Reaction Battalion.
準備行動，夥計們
Stand by, guys!
這種槍我從沒見過 你見過這個麼？
This gun I've never seen. Have you seen this?
這真是太令人驚訝了！看看這槍 這是什麼槍
This is amazing! Look at this gun. What gun is this?
這無疑非常令人驚訝
This is absolutely amazing!
你在做什麼？ 我想把這個給托馬斯看
-What are you doing? -I wanna show this to Thomas.
但我想你說你應付不了它
But I thought you said you can't handle it.
不，我不是應付它 我只是展示它
No, I am not handling it, I'm just gonna show it.
我不打算使用它 人類甚至不能使用
I'm not gonna use it, man. It doesn't even work with humans.
托馬斯，看看這只槍
Thomas, look at this gun!
- 那不是我的 - 你是個軍火商？ -不是
-That's not mine. -You're a dealer, eh? -No.
你聽到了嗎？ 你看到發生的一切嗎？
You hear this, sir? You see what's happening?
第一營，我的朋友 你們知道這意味著什麼
First Battalion, my friend. You know what that means?
這意味著你逍遙法外的日子結束了
That means that your days of flaunting the law are over.
看一看，你看到那了嗎？ 那是什麼？
Have a look, you see that? What's that?
那是一支武裝部隊
That's a firing team.
過來
Come here!
維庫斯！你沒事吧？
Wikus! Are you all right?
你以為你在幹什麼，阿？
Where do you think you're going, eh?
在刀槍面前，你跑不了
You don't run away from the chopper. -No, no...
你以為你能跑到哪？ 你想惹毛我？
Where do you think you're going? You wanna piss me off?
庫布斯呼叫基地
Koobus to base, come in!
我們有兩個人受傷了 MNU警衛，MNU探員
I've got two people down. MNU guard, MNU agent.
我是福克斯特勒特·楊基， 5-3-0，收到？
It's the Foxtrot Yankee 5-3-0... copy?
我們需要醫護隊，盡快
And we need a Med Evac ASAP.
不用，沒事，庫布斯 我並不需要醫護人員
No, that's fine, Koobus. I don't need a Med Evac.
維庫斯，你的手燒傷了 你得...
Wikus, you burned your arm, you need to...
我就在這裡治療就行了，庫布斯
I'll just treat it here, Koobus.
先生，我真的認為你必須看看醫生 進醫生或者啥的
Sir, I really think you must go to a doctor, a hospital or something.
不，不 你得去醫院檢查一下
-No, no. -You should just get it checked out.
上點藥就好了 扶我起來
I'll just have it treated by the medics. Help me up.
特雷特，你看到大蝦跑得有多快了嗎？
Did you see how fast that prawn was, Trent?
是的，他相當的快 告訴你，他相當的快
-Yeah, he was fast. -He was fast, I promise you.
看，我修好它了 它能工作了
Look, I fix it. I make it work.
告訴過你別碰它
I told you not to touch that.
有什麼問題？
What is wrong?
沒事，出去放風去
Nothing. Go outside and watch for humans.
你的朋友呢？
Where is your friend?
他死了
He's gone.
你沒事吧？ 沒事，就是感覺有點熱
Are you okay? -Yeah, I'm just a bit hot.
你們覺得熱嗎？ 你覺得熱嗎，特雷特？  不熱
Are you guys hot? Are you hot, Trent? -No.
是的，怕熱就別進廚房
Yeah, if you can't stand the heat get out of the kitchen.
現在，你看看 到處都是小孩
Now you see. There's kids everywhere.
這就是我的意思 這就是我們要擺脫他們的原因
This is what I mean. That's why we get rid of them.
小傢伙 是的，這就是我們為什麼要讓他們墮胎
-The little ones. -Yeah, that's why we abort.
讓我們乾脆一槍斃了他們 別，別，別，現在別開槍
Lets just shoot the little bastard. -No, no, don't shoot it now.
MNU探員，出來！
MNU agents! Come out!
你好，小傢伙 MNU為你帶來了糖果
Hello, little guy. MNU has sweets for you.
去吧，吃你的糖果
There you go, eat your sweety.
吃起來甜甜的 這個方法每一次都非常靈驗
You know, eaty sweety. Works like a charm every time.
哦，去你媽的，死小孩
Oh fuck, man!
你差點用棒棒糖把我的眼睛戳出來了
You almost poked my eye out with the fokkin' lollypop.
死小孩，我盡量對你和氣了
I tried to be fokkin' nice to you, man!
這是你們家的小畜生嗎
Is this your fokkin' little brat here?
進去 對不起，對不起
Inside, go! I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
管教一下他 托馬斯，讓他出來
Teach him some manners. Thomas, get him out.
出來！跪下，我早已受夠了你們的愚蠢的遊戲
Come! Get down! I've had enough of your stupid games.
你們想要做什麼
What do you want?
我們是MNU的工作人員 我知道
We're from MNU. -I know.
我們要你在這個驅逐通知單上蓋個手印
We require your scrawl on this eviction notification.
- 我為什麼要被驅逐？ - 是的，這是一個驅逐通知單
-Why am I being evicted? -Yes, it's an eviction notice.
把你的手印按在底下 看到沒？你的名字在上面
Put your scrawl on the bottom. See? There's your name at the top.
- 是的！-克裡斯多夫·約翰遜? - 所以在底部按上你的名字
-Yes! -Christopher Johnson? So, put your name in the bottom.
這裡說你們必須24小時前通知我
It says you must give me 24 hours notice.
你們將到另一個地方 一個專為你們而新建的更好的城市
You're going to another place. A nice new city built especially for prawns.
- 一個很特別的地方 -而且我們還不向你們收費，明白嗎？
-A special place! -And we are not even going to charge you, okay?
- 這不合法 - 簽字！   - 不！
This isn't legal. -Sign the fokkin' paper! -No!
這個傢伙很明顯 他聰明點
This guy is obviously... he's a little sharper.
所以我們要另想辦法
So we are gonna have to try something else.
好的，你好...聽我說
All right. Hello... okay.
看來我們有些地方沒有說明白，嗯
Seems like we didn't understand each other there properly, eh?
在這裡你還有孩子
So, you've got a little one there.
- 那小孩有辦出生證明嗎？ - 有的
Do you have a licence for that little one? -Yes.
這裡周圍都是垃圾場 這對你孩子的生存很不利
There's a litter out here. This is dangerous conditions for your child.
75條文件說因為你的小孩生活在 一個危險的環境中
Article 75 says that because your child is living in dangerous
我們會把他帶到兒童福利院去
conditions, I'm gonna take him down to Child Services.
我要跟你的孩子談談
I'm gonna go and have a little chat with your son.
離我孩子遠點
You keep away from my child!
別用那骯髒的觸手指著我
Don't point your fokkin' tentacles at me!
你說你想呆在這？
You said you want to stay?
你的孩子將要和我一起去福利院
Your boy is coming down with me to Child Services.
他的下半輩子就只能在1×1米的箱子裡度過了
He's gonna spend the rest of his life in 1 by 1 meter box.
你好，小傢伙，可愛的叔叔過來了
Hello, little guy! It's the sweety man coming!
操，看看這個，特雷特！ 操他媽的！
Fuck, look at this, Trent! Fuck it!
托馬斯，拿槍指著他 他是徹頭徹尾的罪犯
Thomas, keep the gun on him. He is definitely a criminal!
這裡簡直是個電腦商店
He's got a whole computer shop here, man!
我是說，這裡太讓人驚訝了，這裡顯然是一個
You know, this is amazing. I mean, this is obviously...
你現在可以看到這些失竊的電腦 被他用來作為房子的裝飾
you can see stolen computers now that he's decorating his place with.
很明顯，他沒有許可做這事
Definitely he doesn't have the permit for this.
那小毛孩哪去了？
Where is that fokkin' little brat?
你在哪呀？我那個可愛的叔叔喔
Hello! It's the sweety man...
這裡有糖果 嘿，我找到了...
It's the sweety... Hey, I've got this...
- 維庫斯! - 特雷特,關了它
-Wikus! -Trent, turn it off!
- 你沒事吧，頭？ - 後退，後退！
Are you okay, boss? -Fuck off, man! Fuck off!
- 扔下他不管嗎？ - 就把他留在這裡吧
Shall I leave him? -Just fuckin' leave him, yeah.
明天我會過來見你的，克裡斯多夫·約翰遜.
I'll see you tomorrow, Christopher Johnson.
當你和外星人打交道時 態度要和藹，但立場要堅定
When dealing with aliens, try to be polite, but firm.
並且永遠記住微笑比子彈便宜
And always remember that a smile is cheaper than a bullet.
- 感覺好些了嗎？ - 什麼？你覺得怎樣了？
Are you feeling better? -What? -How are you feeling?
我很好，我沒事 我只是有點頭暈
I'm fine, I'm alright. I'm just a little bit dizzy.
能在那邊停一下嗎？
Can you just pull up there on the side?
我想在那吃點東西
I just want to get something to eat here.
你確定你要吃這些？
Are you sure you should be having that?
在你大吐那麼長時間後
After your whole puking episode?
我感覺很好多了...我想 我需要補充能量
I feel a lot better... I think I just needed the fillings, you know.
頭！頭！
Boss! Boss!
有黑色的東西從你鼻子裡流出來了
There's black stuff coming out of your nose.
天呀！
Jesus!
還有一個銀造的圓筒 我找不到他了
It's a silver cylinder. I can't find it.
我一定得找到他 它裡面有流體
We must find it. It contains the fluid.
它不在這裡了
It's not here.
它應該在這裡，繼續找
It has to be. Keep looking.
我們要一萬罐
We trade for ten thousand cans.
尼日利亞幫派
Certain factions of nigerian gangs
想把第九區的外星武器全部購買完
want to try and extract weaponry from District 9.
他們已經嘗試了好多年
And have been trying to for many many years.
-給他100罐 - 100  - 100罐
Give them one hundred cans. -Hundred. -One hundred!
好的，好的 這次我們全要了
Yes, yes, but we take them all now.
好的，夥計們！ 給他們貓糧～抓緊了
Alright, boys! Get them the catfood - hurry up.
他們收集了大量的外星武器
And they amassed thousands of these weapons.
卻無法使用它們
Without the ability to use them.
滾開！走！ 嘿，朋友，不是你，你呆在這
Fuck off! Go! Hey friend, not you. You stay here.
你想要什麼 我想和你談談
-What do you want from me? -I just want to talk.
談什麼？
Talk about what?
愚蠢的蝦 他們什麼都相信
Stupid prawn. They'll believe anything.
「Muti」是個南非詞
Muti is a South African word.
和魔法或巫術的意思類似
Today it's synonymous with witchdoctory and magic.
從這裡把它切開 這是他們的心臟
You cut it here. This is their heart.
煮來吃能夠治癒高血壓
Cures high blood when you boil it,
治癒高血糖，糖尿病 能包治百病
cures sugar, diabetes, all diseases.
尼日利亞人食用外星人
The nigerians were consuming alien body parts.
他們相信這樣做可以獲取外星人的能力
They believed that by doing so, they were ingesting their power
從而就可以使用他們的武器
to use alien weaponry.
你必須吃掉它們
You must eat them.
這樣他們的能力才能轉移到你的體內
And their power will live in you.
給我個機會跑在你的前面，媽的
Just give me a fucking chance to go in front of you, man!
哦，寶貝！-嗨，寶貝，進來 我想去趟廁所
Oh, baby! -Hi baby, come in! -I need to get to the toilet, quickly!
為什麼？怎麼了？
Why? What's the matter?
寶貝，聽著，我可能尿褲子了 -驚喜嗎！
Baby, listen. I might have crapped in my pants. -Surprise!
這是幹什麼？ -慶祝你的升職呀 對，我升職了
What's this for? -Your promotion. -All right, my promotion!
爸，過得怎樣？ 媽，很高興見到你
Hello, dad. How is it going? Hi mom. -Good to see you.
太驚喜了 祝賀你  -謝謝
What a surprise, man! -Congratulations. -Thanks.
祝賀你，頭兒 -謝謝
Congratulations, boss. -Thank you.
維庫斯，出什麼事了？ 寶貝，就是出了點小意外
-Wikus, what happened? -I had a small incident, baby.
我得去趟廁所 然後再回來跟大伙聊聊，好嗎？
I'm just gonna go to the toilet, and then I'll talk to people, okay?
我得和你談談，和我一起來 -好的，不過我得...
I need to talk to you. Come with me. -Okay, but I just gotta...
夥計們，稍等我們一會？
Guys, can you give us a moment, please?
那邊出什麼事了？
What happened out there?
那些大蝦們根本不肯聽我的 其中一個還特別不守規矩
This prawn wouldn't listen to me, one really unruly prawn...
而我不得不 親自抓住他
and I just had to... get him in my grasp.
聽我說，那裡今天死了很多外星人.
Listen to me, too many aliens died out there today.
我身後全是UIO的人
UYO is all over my backside.
聽我說！你可別給我搞砸了
Focus! you're not going to fuck this up for me!
如果你無法勝任這工作 我就另找他人
If you can't do the job, I'll find someone who can!
- 嗨，你們好！ - 很高興又見到你們
Hi there! -Nice to see you again.
這是不是意味著他要接管這次新的行動？
Does this mean he's in charge of this new operation?
- 是的 - 那太好了
-Yes. -That's nice.
維庫斯！寶貝，你還好嗎？
Wikus! Baby are you okay?
好了，讓我們來切蛋糕
Okay, let's cut some cake.
史密斯醫生，請到405房間來
Doctor Smith, please come to room 405, doctor Smith.
- 是不是感染的特別嚴重？ - 這有很多腐肉
Is it badly infected? -There's a lot of suppuration.
還有你應該知道我的右手一些手指甲變得很鬆動
Also you should know on my right hand some fingernails were coming loose.
還有黑色的液體從我鼻子裡流出來 並嘔吐過黑色物
And I had a black fluid coming out of my nose, and sort of a black vomit.
我的手怎麼了 醫生
What is happening to my arm, doctor?
這是什麼東西？
What is this thing?
深呼吸 別緊張，平靜點
Just breathe deeply. Calm down. Stay calm.
請叫我的妻子來
Sir, please tell my wife.
請注意，所有11區的病人，迅速隔離
Attention all medical containment evacuate ward 11.
停下，女士
Stop right there, madam.
怎麼了？ 你們要對他做什麼？
What's going on? What are you doing to him?
讓我進去！
Let me through!
維庫斯! 維庫斯! 你們要把他帶到哪去？
Wikus! Wikus! Where are you taking him?
好，抓住他了？ 準備好了？抓住了
Okay, got him? Are you ready? -Got him.
我們決定不用麻醉劑
We decided not to use the anesthetic,
因為我們不知道他會產生什麼反應
the reason being we can't know how the subject will react.
Fester醫生  -什麼事? 我想你應該看看這個
Doctor Fester! -Yes? -I think you should see this.
我在他的夾克裡發現了這個 這是外星人的嗎？
I found it in his jacket. You think this is alien?
停下，冷死了！去你媽的！
Stop, it's freezing! Fuck!
暴露16個小時
16 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
這是哪？
Where is this?
什麼？
What?
他們對這些大蝦都做什麼了？
What are they doing to these prawns?
痛閾測試，第一次，DBX7
Pain threshold, test one, DBX 7.
有很強的疼痛反應 說明神經系統已經形成
That's a strong pain reaction. That means the nerves have fused.
意思是，幾乎融為了一體
I mean, it's almost completely integrated.
好吧，開始吧
Okay, do it.
B5，測試AMR-B5
B5. Testing AMR-B5.
清理障礙 現在就要，快點
Clear the range. Now, quickly!
轉過來
Swing it around.
你們要做什麼？ 們是鎖著的
What are you doing? -The door is locked.
你能握住這個嗎？ 這是什麼？
Can you grip that? -What is this?
手扣進去 你們要我幹啥
-Put it through. -Why are you doing this?
預備開火，預備 你們要我射擊那個？
-Standby for fire. Standby. -You want me to shoot that?
退回...開火
Stand back... and fire!
很好
That's good!
奏效了
It worked!
好了，謝謝你
All right, thanks very much.
你知道我的妻子在哪嗎？
Do you know where my wife is?
我妻子知道我在這裡嗎？
Do you know if my wife knows where I am, sir?
扣動扳機！扣動扳機
Pull! Pull!
不，我不扣
No sir, I will not pull.
你剛說老婆怎麼來著？ 去他媽的，你老婆
What did you say about your wife? Fuck your wife!
- 扣動扳機！ - 我不扣！
Pull! -I will not pull.
開火！
Fire!
B7  -我可以扣動它 - 他說他能扣動它
B7. -I can pull it. -He says he can pull it.
我說我能扣動它 你他媽...
I said I could pull it! You fuckin'...!
B21
B21.
過去，快點 過去
Move, hurry up. Move!
- 現在，把它安置到鐵鏈中間 - 放開我
Right, we want him in the center by the chain. -Get this off me.
快點！快點！
Come on! Time, time!
把他媽的大蝦弄走 我朝豬開槍就是了，我開槍就是了
Leave that fucking prawn, man, I will shoot at pig. I'll shoot, sir!
聽我說，我會為你朝豬肉開槍 我會開槍的
Listen, I'll shoot at pig again for you. I'll pull the trigger.
但我不會朝大蝦開槍 聽到了嗎？拿走這些該死的槍
But I'm not shooting at prawn, you hear me? Untie the fucking gun.
人手扣動B21，非常不錯 成功了
B21 in human hand. That's good. It worked.
拿走這槍 閃開
Just untie the gun, sir. -Stand by.
聽我說，不能拿生命做實驗 他又沒有惹你
Listen, you can't use the real guy, he didn't do anything to you.
我要試試這個 所有的人閃開
I want to try this. Everybody standing by.
準備好沒？ 3，2，1，開槍！
Ready to go? Three, two, one, go!
太不可思議了！
Amazing!
好了 試驗到此為止了
All right! I think that's all we need.
先生們，我們時間不多了
Gentlemen, we are running out of time.
這是變形的關鍵階段
This is the key stage in the metamorphosis.
他的DNA是人類和外星人的完美結合
His DNA is in perfect balance between alien and human.
但問題是，隨著感染的擴大
And a problem is, as the infection spreads,
這個轉變會變得永久的 並且越來越沒有活力的
the transition becomes permanent and less active.
他將變成外星人的一員 變成一隻大蝦
He's going to turn into one of them. A prawn!
他變成什麼不重要
What happens to him isn't important.
重要的是我們現在能從他身上獲取什麼
What's important is that we harvest from him what we can right now.
這個軀體價值好幾百萬
This body represents hundreds of millions,
甚至是價值幾億美元的生物技術
maybe billions of dollars worth of biotechnology.
政府、公司所有人都會為
There are people out there, governments, corporations,
這個東西拚個你死我活
who'd kill for this chance.
他能挺得過這些程序嗎？ 不，當然不能了
Will he survive the procedure? -No, of course not.
我們要他所有的東西 組織，骨髓，血液
We need everything. Tissue, bone marrow, blood.
這個過程會把他拆得一無所有
The procedure is gonna basically strip him down to nothing. -Please...
親屬們怎麼安置？
What about next of kin?
求求你幫幫我 別讓他們這樣做
Please help me. Don't let them do it.
我會處理那些
I'll handle that.
好吧，開始吧 好的，謝謝
Okay, I say let's go. -Good, thank you.
我不明白
I don't understand.
一切都說不通 他只是手臂受傷了，爸
None of this makes any sense. He just hurt his arm, dad.
醫生們盡力了，親愛的
The doctors are trying, sweetheart.
盡一切所能在挽救他們的生命
Doing their best to save him.
我們已經開始從樣本上收穫材料了
We're starting to harvest material from the specimen.
我們首先從軟組織開始 先剖開胸膛
We'll start with the soft tissue first. Cut through the chest cavern.
我們必須盡快取出心臟
We need to get the heart out as quickly as possible.
一旦感染病毒了，病毒會飛快傳播
Once it set the sinuosity, it just spread.
你一向知道維庫斯 他並不那麼強壯
You know Wikus. He never was very strong.
我來切開胸膛，取出心臟
I'll go through the chest, go straight into the heart.
安靜些 操你媽！
Be quiet, please. -Fuck you!
我能見見他嗎？
Can I see him?
還是不見好
Not a good idea.
走開！操你媽！
Fuck off! Fuck you!
操你媽！
Fuck you!
放下刀
Drop the knife!
走開否則我將割破他的喉嚨
Move or I'll fuckin' cut his throat!
好的，好吧！
Okay. All right!
我會殺了他
I'll fuckin' kill him!
你得對他放手了
You need to let go of him now.
沒事的，蒂尼婭 一切都會好起來的
It's okay, Tania. Everything will be okay.
史密斯
Smith.
什麼時候？
When?
快叫庫布斯
Get Koobus.
維庫斯·范德默爾
...Wikus Van De Merwe.
白人，男性 30多歲 高度危險人物
White male, mid thirties. Is considered highly dangerous.
嘿，寶貝 維庫斯，是你嗎？
-Hey baby. -Wikus, is that you?
Smith夫人？ 你竟敢給我打電話！
-Mrs. Smith? -How dare you phone us!
你們這些人在我家裡幹嘛？ 不干你的事
What are all these people doing in my house? -It's none of your business.
我得和蒂尼婭談談 馬上走開，這是我的房子
I need to speak to Tania straight away, please. It's my house.
你用的是我的電話，我是...什麼？
This is my phone that you're using, mam. I'm fokkin'... what?
他想給我打電話
He tried calling me.
Anton，是我，快接電話
Anton, it's me! It's me! Accept the call!
我們都有13年的交情了
I've been friends with you for fokkin' 13 years, man!
滾開！你在看什麼？ 滾遠點
Fuck off! What are you watching? Fuck off!
我們都認為這是出於好意 因為他需要幫助
We all thought it was for the best because he needed help.
需要特殊醫療幫助
A special medical help.
而如果他繼續逃亡的話就無法得到 醫療幫助
And he wasn't gonna get that as a fugitive.
他已經成為世界上 最具商業價值的人了
He became the most valuable business artifact on Earth.
他是唯一一個能夠
He was the only human who had ever...
成功和外星基因結合 並還活著的人
successfully been combined with alien genetics and remained alive.
不過他真正的價值在於 他能夠使用外星武器
But his real value was that he could operate alien weaponry.
你好
Hello.
能給我些奶酪漢堡和泡菜嗎？
Can I get some cheese burgers and one large sauerkraut, please.
我們中斷這個節目並給大家帶來一個 驚人的消息
We interrupt this program to bring you breaking news.
有病人從隔離病房逃走 並且在這個城市逃亡
A patient has escaped from the isolation ward and is loose in the city.
維庫斯·范德默爾已經被證實
Wikus Van De Merwe was recently apprehended
在第九區和外星人有長期的性行為
after prolonged sexual activity with aliens in District 9.
一派胡言 我得給我的經理人打電話
This is nonsense. -I have to call my manager.
這簡直是一派胡言 你本該受命於我的
That is totally untrue. You are legally obliged to serve me!
已經導致他的身體發生變形
...is causing bodily disfigurement.
我只想要買我的漢堡 別聽他們胡說
If I could just buy my burger, please. Don't listen to them!
這具有高度的傳染性 警方警告民眾
It's highly contagious and the police warns people
至少要與這個人保持20米的距離
to stay at least 20 meters away from this man.
別看這個手 這個手沒事
Don't look at this hand! This hand is fine!
如果你有此人的任何消息
If you have any information regarding the whereabouts
請立即通知我們
of Mr Van De Merwe, contact us immediately on 0800-stop-wikus.
別動！
Stop!
暴露31小時後
31 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
你好，這是蒂尼婭 還有維庫斯
Hi, this is Tania. -And Wikus.
我們暫時不能接聽電話
We can't come to the phone right now.
請留言，拜拜
Please leave a message. Bye. -Bye bye.
總部，這裡還沒有維庫斯的消息
Control, there's no sign of mr Van De Merwe.
全世界的人都在關注他
The entire world was watching him.
廣播、電視台到處都在報道他
He was on every radio station, every image on television,
到處都是他的照片
anything you could find had his face on it.
他已經無路可逃 他只有一個地方可取
So he had nowhere else to go. He ended up hiding in the one place
他知道沒人會去找他
he knew no one would ever come looking for him.
暴露40小時後
40 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
給現錢，不然別想
Pay now,or nothing.
下周給你，我保證
I pay you next week, I promise.
沒錢，什麼都不給 該死的大蝦，這不是慈善
No money - you get nothing. Fucking prawn, this isn't charity.
你好，我想買一些肉
Hello, I'd like to buy some meat, please.
嘿，一個人！
Hey, a man!
是的，你這裡有漢堡 或者牛排卷嗎？
Yes, have you got a hamburger, or a steak roll?
難道這裡看起來像是漢堡店？
Does it look like a hamburger shop?
你要什麼肉？ 羊肉？
Which one do you want? Goat?
快點，快點 我可沒閒工夫
Come on, come on, I don't have the whole day.
那是貓糧嗎？ 是的，那是貓糧
Is that a cat food there? -Yeah, yeah, it is.
那來點貓糧
I'll have some of that, guys.
我操！
Fuck, man!
喂，喂
Hello, hello?
寶貝是你嗎？蒂尼婭？
Baby is that you? Tania?
天呀，希望一定是你
God, please let it be you.
是的，是我
Yes, it's me.
我真是太高興了 你給我打電話了，寶貝
I'm so happy you called me, baby.
維庫斯，聽我說 -好的
-Wikus, listen to me. -Okay.
我有些事情想對你說 而這真難開口
I have something to say to you, and it's not gonna be easy.
不，不，看...聽著，寶貝 在你說任何事情前...
No, no, look... listen baby, before you say anything...
你父親不站在我這邊 而且他欺騙了你
Your father is working against me, but he's lying to you.
我從來沒有跟這些
I did not have sex with one of these...
和那些外星人發生過性關係
...fokkin' creatures, man!
我絕不會和那種東西
I would never have any kind of
產生任何形式的衝動和性行為
pornographic activity with a fokkin' creature!
他們說你變成了他們的一員 我實在無法接受這點...
They say that you're becoming one of them. I can't do this...
寶貝，求你了，請別放棄我
Baby please, don't give up on me.
千萬別放棄我 因為我可以...
Don't give up on me baby, because I can...
我想再次見到你，寶貝
I want to see you again, baby.
我的手會好起來的 而且我會再次見到你的
I'm gonna fix my arm and I'm gonna see you again,
到時我要親吻你 要把你摟在懷中
and I'm gonna kiss you and I'm gonna hold you again.
我也希望你能再一次抱著我
I also want you to hold me again.
寶貝
Baby?
嗨，嗨，老兄！
Hey! Hey man!
好的...
...
我們現在直接搜索那個位置
We are on tracking directly to the location.
收到，我會給你一些支援備用的直升機
Roger that. I'll send you a couple of choppers for backup.
你！
You!
你想幹嘛？
What do you want?
總部，發現一個目標移動到66
Come in, control, there is our target moving to 66.
- 你得走了 - 求你了，我需要你的幫忙
-You have to go. -Please, I need your help.
- 我們來玩捉迷藏 - 好的！好的！   不，退後
We're gonna play hide and seek. -Yes! Yes! -No, get back.
你應該讓我藏起來？ 告訴我你最喜歡藏在哪？
You want me to hide? Show me your favorite hiding place.
走吧，求你了，離我們遠點
Please, just go. Leave us alone.
不，求求你了，我得藏起來
No, please, I need to hide.
他們會殺了我的
They wanna kill me.
我只需要在這裡藏起來 就5分鐘，好嗎？
I just need to hide in here, sir, for 5 minutes, okay?
這是什麼？ 你們在這裡幹什麼？
What is this? What are you doing here?
- 我記得你  - 什麼都沒 - 你一定能藏在什麼地方
-I remember you. -Nothing. You must hide somewhere else.
先生...求求你了 你得幫幫我
Sir... please sir, you have to help me.
我流血不止 他們要殺了我
I'm losing blood, they're trying to kill me.
只有一種東西能讓那個發生...
Only one thing that could make that happen...
快！我們得把他藏起來
Quick! We have to hide him.
你...，下去
Now you... get down there.
流體在哪？ 你們拿它幹什麼了？
Where's the fluid? What did you do with it?
求你了！ 你拿走了它...
-Please! -You took it...
我不知道你 在說什麼
I don't know what you're talking about!
...我知道你拿走了它 我可以看出你身上發生的反應
...I know you did. I can see what's happening to you.
告訴我它在哪裡？
Tell me where it is.
好的，好的
Alright, alright.
它是不是一個長容器裡面的黑色液體？
Was it a black fluid in a flask container?
是的，就是它，是的！
Yes, that's it. Yes!
我把它沒收了 實驗室的人拿走了它
I confiscated it and the guys at the lab took it.
它肯定在MNU MNU的人拿著他
It will be at the MNU. MNU has it.
那是什麼東西？
What is this?
- 你毀掉了一切 - 那東西現在在哪？
-You ruined everything. -Where is this?
這是你的房子？
Is that your shack?
這一切的東西都在你房子下面？
This whole thing is under your shack?
20年來，你一直在這裡放 你那些重要的東西
For 20 years you've... had this fokking' thing in here?
天呀，這是嚴重違法的
Jesus, this is very illegal.
我在說，這簡直是個大發現 真希望他們能逮你個正著
I mean, this is a find, you know. I wish they catch you with this.
能量從這裡進去
Fuel goes in here.
夠了！安靜！
That's enough! Quiet!
然後我們就可以飛走了
Then we fly away.
我說安靜 我們不能相信他
I said quiet! We cannot trust him.
他說的能量是什麼？ 你們打算開動飛船嗎？
What is he saying about the fuel? Are you trying to start this thing?
你們這些傻瓜要開動飛船然後飛走？
Are you little fuckers trying to start this and get away?
算了吧
Never mind.
你們這些鬼鬼祟祟的大蝦
Yeah, you sneaky fokkin' prawns.
太糟了，我本來可以治好你的
Too bad. I could've fixed you.
什麼？你說的治好是什麼意思？
What? What did you say... about the fixing?
你說你能治好我是什麼意思
What do you mean you could fix me?
算了吧，沒用了，太晚了
Forget it. It doesn't matter, it's too late.
不，聽著！聽著 你是說你可以
No, listen! Listen. Are you saying that you can...
把我這隻大蝦手變成人手？
turn this prawn hand into a human hand?
你可以讓變回人類？
You can make me human again?
我們主船上有醫療設備能夠治好你的病
We have medical machines on the mothership that can fix you. Yes.
我們可以開這個小船飛到上面去
We can use this ship to fly up there.
那太好了！ 你們真是太聰明了！
That's fantastic! You guys are brilliant!
我一直都認為大蝦們很聰明 那我們開工吧
I always thought that prawns were intelligent. Let's do it.
我沒有流體
I don't have fluid.
我可以治好你，也能飛走 但我沒有流體
I could fix you and I could fly away. But I don't have fluid.
對，好的
Right, okay.
好吧，我來告訴你怎樣 我們為什麼不...
All right, I tell you what. Why don't we...
再冒險一次，我們再去收集一些
go risk it some more? Let's go collect some up.
我們花了20年才收集到那一點
It took twenty years to collect that amount.
我操！操！
Fuck, man! Fuck!
操！唯一的那一點還被我沒收了？
Fuck! The only one that exists is the one I confiscated?
是的
Yes.
這是地下四層
It's four stories underground.
- 他為什麼一直那樣看著我？ - 他喜歡你
Why does he keep looking at me like that? -He likes you.
我們是同類
We are the same.
我們不是同類 我們他媽的不是同類
We're not the same. We're not the fokkin' same.
只剩一個辦法讓我們脫離這個困境了 我們得從MNU手上拿回流體
There is a way out of this. We get the fluid back from MNU.
是呀，然後怎麼辦？ 然後我們兩兩都歸西？
Yeah, and what then? Then we both die, eh?
我們都會死 這簡直是個自殺行動
Both of us dead. That's a suicide mission, man.
你能不能別給我灌輸這些愚蠢的主意
Can you not fill my head with that sort of nonsense?
變形正在加速
The transformation is accelerating.
你時間已經所剩無幾
You don't have much time.
暴露56小時後
56 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
操！操！操
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
喂
Hello.
維庫斯？ 蒂尼婭！寶貝
-Wikus? -Tania! Baby...
你沒事吧？ 哦，天呀！謝天謝地...
-Are you okay? -Oh God! Thank God...
你在哪？
Where are you?
我在...
I'am...
我知道我父親對我撒了謊 我知道他在試圖保護我
It's not like my father said. I know he was lying to protect me.
我不知道該相信什麼了
I just don't know what to believe anymore.
寶貝，我懂！但是請聽我說
Baby I know, but listen to me.
這一切都是謊言，我向你發誓 他所說的一切都是謊言
It's all lies, I swear to you. Everything he said to you is lies.
我知道 什麼？什麼？
-I know. -What? What?
我相信你，維庫斯 我只希望你回來
I believe you, Wikus. I just want you back.
我想要讓一切都回到它應有的狀態
I want everything back the way it was.
這...寶貝，這也是我想要的
That's... baby, that's what I want.
太好了 真的太好了
That's great! That's great news.
我可以讓一切回到過去那樣 如果你還要我的話
I can make it the way it was. If you take me back.
怎樣？我們怎樣才能回到過去？
How? How can we go back?
我有個計劃 我知道怎麼治好它
I have a plan. I know how to fix it.
我知道怎麼治好自己的病
I know how to fix myself.
然後我又是我了 我們將會重新在一起
And it will be me. And we'll be back together.
你發誓？ 我想你發誓，寶貝
-You promise me? -I promise you, baby.
別放棄我，好嗎？
Don't give up on me, okay?
因為我還沒放棄你，好嗎？
Because I haven't given up on you. All right?
我永遠不會放棄你的
I won't.
我愛你 我也愛你
-I love you. -I love you too.
告訴我你已經定位到他了
Tell me you got a fix on him. -D9.
我們的星球有幾個月亮呢？
How many moons does our planet have?
7個
Seven.
這個地球只有一個
This planet only has one.
我等不及見到我們的星球了 它比地球還大，是嗎？
I can't wait to see our planet. It's bigger than this one, isn't it?
大多了
Enough.
我們現在可以回家了？
We go home now?
還不能回家，不能
Not home. No.
這個地方我們必須去一趟
This is where we must go.
看到那裡的帳篷了嗎？ 那是我們的
See that tent there? That might be ours.
我想回家
I want to go home!
我們回不了家了 再也回不去了
We can't go home. Not anymore.
喂，你不會想去那裡的 那裡一定不好
Hi, you don't wanna go to the tents, they are not better.
那裡比這裡還小
They're smaller than the shacks.
實際上，它更像是一個集中營
Actually, more like a concentration camp.
如果我能幫你拿回黑色流體 然後怎樣？
If I can get you that black fluid, what happens then?
我們進入母船
We go up to the mothership.
然後你可以啟動那玩意？ 是的
And you can start that thing? -Yes.
好的，那麼讓我們說清楚了 這手將會回到...
Okay, so just to be clear: this is gonna go back...
這手將會回到原來的樣子
This is gonna go back to human like this.
我可以回家，你也可以回家
I can go home and then you can go home.
你可以帶上你的小孩 你可以帶上所有的大蝦
You can take your boy, you can take all the prawns,
如果我能帶來流體的話，對嗎？
if I can get you that fluid, right?
你說過這是一個自尋死路的任務 你可能是對的
You said it was a suicide mission. Maybe you were right.
我們沒有武器 他們一看到我們就會開槍
We have no weapons. They'll shoot us on sight.
看，看... 克裡斯多夫
Look, look... Christopher...
我知道到哪裡可以找到武器
I know where we can get weapons.
喂，夥計們，你們好
Hi guys. Hello.
我想買點武器
I would like to buy some weapons, please.
你究竟是怎麼做到的？
How did you do this like that?
和外星人來後背式
A doggie style with the demon.
我喜歡它
I love it!
一個勇敢的白人男人 哦？ 當時戴安全套了嗎？
One brave white man, eh? Were you wearing a condom?
我想要買武器，拜託了
I need to buy weapons, please.
你和我都知道裡面都是些非法武器
You and I both know that there are illegal weapons inside here.
我帶來了錢 我想那些武器
I have money and I would like to buy some of those...
坐下
Sit!
謝謝你了，先生，佔用你時間了 非常感激你的接見
Thank you sir for your time. Thank you very much for seeing me.
我想買些武器
I would like to buy some weapons.
AK-47，一些手榴彈 催淚瓦斯也行
AK-47, some grenades... maybe tear gas canisters.
我知道你還有些武器在那裡 我..
I see you have limpet mines here aswell, and I..
還看到過你們有外星人的武器 非常強大的武器
also see you guys have alien weapons there, which is great!
我能買一兩件這種武器嗎？
If I could have one or two of those.
我帶來了錢，好嗎？ 現在，我...
I have money, okay? Now, I'm...
先生，求你了，先生！
Sir! Please, sir!
我聽說過你
I've heard about you.
你哪裡變形了？ 給我看看
Where do you have it? Show me!
哦，媽的
Oh, shit!
過來，過來
Come here. Come.
別，別...請別這樣
No, no... don't please!
你們這是幹嘛？ 你要幹嘛？
Why are you doing this? What do you want?
閉嘴！
Shut up!
再也不說武器了 再也不說武器了
Forget the weapons! Forget the weapons!
我要這隻手，砍下來
I want the arm. Cut it off.
他說什麼？
What is he saying?
我做給你看
I'll show you.
我的娘呀！
Holy shit!
告訴他們退下
You tell them to stand down!
告訴他們安靜點 後退
You tell them to be quiet! To back off!
讓他們把武器裝到口袋裡
Tell them to put the fokkin' weapons in the bag!
把武器給我，他媽的混蛋
Give me the fokkin' weapons, man!
別這樣，看著我
Don't you, sir, look at me.
我說了，別盯著我看
I said don't fokkin' look at me!
你究竟是如何長出這隻手的？
How did you get that hand?
快點
Fokkin' hurry up there!
當我跟你說話時，你他媽看著我 你有什麼秘密
Look at me when I fuckin' speak to you. What is your secret?
你到底做了什麼？告訴我
What did you do? Tell me!
我想要他媽的那隻手臂 你到底幹了什麼
I want that fuckin' arm. What the fuck did you do?
你這個混蛋 我會去找你的
You fuckin' mazungo, I'm coming for you!
我會去找你的 我會逮著你的
I'm coming for you and I'm gonna get you!
放下刀 放下刀
Drop your fokkin' knife. Drop your fokkin' knife!
他對我們毫無用處 你就不能放鬆點
He's useless to us dead. -Would you relax?
為他媽的緣故，我手下應付這種事情 至少有100遍了
For fuck's sakes, my men have done this a hundred times before.
將獵物保持在視線範圍內
Maintaining a visual on the location.
一切都會很快了結的
It's gonna be quick.
一切都會被清理地一乾二淨
It's gonna be clean.
最好的，一切都會無聲無息
Best of all, it's gonna be quiet.
范德默爾還不知道會發生什麼事情
Van De Merwe hasn't got a clue what's coming his way.
沒人！ 他們哪去了？
It's empty! -Where are they?
目標消失了 此地空無一人
Target is gone. The place is empty.
你什麼意思，沒人？ 那他媽到哪去了？
What do you mean, empty? Where the fuck is he?
那個小混蛋根本不知道 接下來會發生什麼
That little shithead has got no idea what is coming his way.
我會找到他的
I'm gonna find him.
那裡有警衛，在門口 小心門口的警衛，夥計
There are the guards! At the gate! Watch the guards at the gate, man!
快點，出去
Move! Get out!
他們下去了 朝4樓去了
They're going down. Four stories down.
這是外星武器 給我現狀報告
This is alien weaponry. Give me a status report.
是范德默爾 他在四樓
It's Van De Merwe. He's on level four.
切換到實彈 我們要把他搜出來
Switch to live, and then we're taking him out.
上校，我們不允許使用實彈
Colonel, we weren't allowed to use live ammunition.
他們想要捉活的
They want him alive.
留在這裡，沒我的允許，先別離開
Stay here until I call you. -I understand.
我得把們打開
I need to get the door open.
不！我說沒我允許，先別離開
No! I said stay until I call you!
操
Fuck!
我還以為你說別殺他們呢？
I thought you said not to kill them?
他朝我開槍
He shot at me!
操！滾出去 別他媽得看著我
Fuck! Get out! Don't fuckin' look at me!
出去，都給我滾出去
Get out! Get the fuck out!
出去 都給我滾出去
Get out! Everybody get the fuck out!
出去，滾
Get out! Go!
移開這些東西！滾！
Move the fuck out! Go!
這是什麼地方「 別操心這個了
What is this place? -Don't worry about that.
他們在這裡想幹啥？
What do they do in here?
搜搜那些盒子
Check these boxes.
所有能裝進管子的盒子都搜查一下 快去
Any type of a box that looks like it can hold a tube. Just check it out!
這些混蛋
These fuckers!
走，走，走
Go, go, go...
沒人
Clear.
找到了，找到了
I got it! I got it!
Chris我找到了，走吧
Chris, I got it. Let's go!
克裡斯多夫！
Christopher!
哦，操！
Oh, fuck!
聽我說...我真不知道他們 在這裡幹什麼
Listen... I promise you, I didn't know they were doing this.
直到他們上次也把我帶進來
Until they brought me here the other day,
我向你發誓，我真的不知道 他們這樣對你們的人
I swear to you I did not know they were doing this to you guys.
克裡斯多夫... 看著我，聽我說
But Christopher... look at me. Listen to me.
我們現在得趕緊走了，好嗎？
We need to leave now. Okay?
整個MNU的人都會下來的
The whole of MNU is gonna come down here.
他們要我們的命的
He's going to destroy us.
我們能辦到的，對嗎？ 我們趕緊離開這裡
We can do this, okay? We're gonna get out of here...
開火！
Fire!
快點，快點
Move, move!
朝大蝦開火
Shoot at the prawn!
克裡斯多夫!你他媽在幹啥？
Christopher! What the fuck are you doing?
想想你的孩子
Think of your boy, for fuck sake!
你究竟在幹啥？ 你瘋了嗎？
What the hell are you doing? Are you out of your fuckin' mind?
你會讓我們都死掉了的 我們現在該怎麼辦？
You're gonna get us killed! -What do we do now?
我以為你知道出路呢？
I thought you had a way out?
我從來沒有提到出路
I didn't say anything about the way out.
我答應過你我們一定能進去 我們的確進來了   -我想到了
-I promised you that we'll get in. We're in! -I have an idea.
你去哪？ 跟著我就是
-Where are you going? -Follow me!
你在做什麼？ 做炸彈
What are you doing? -Making a bomb.
走吧
Let's go!
快點，進來！
Quick! Get in!
走！開車！
Go! Drive!
好的！
Okay!
好的，坐穩了
Okay, hold on!
操！
Fuck!
報道來自約翰內斯堡市中心的一個爆炸
Reports are coming in of explosion in downtown Johannesburg.
那裡遭到了一次恐怖襲擊
Well, there was a terrorist attack,
不過我向你們保證，我們正在處理這事 一切都很正常
but I can assure you that we dealt with it. Everything is fine.
飛低點 飛低點，下降
Droop it down! Droop it down! Decline!
他們裡我們 很近了
They are really close to us now!
糟糕
Shit!
走，快走
Let's go, let's go!
別把那他媽的流體弄丟了
Don't drop that fokkin' thing!
快點，快，下來
Come on, move! Get down there!
下去並輸入啟動命令
Go down and initiate the binary commands.
趕緊降落
Set it down right now!
我們到達主船時，還要多久才能治好
When we get up to the mothership, how long is this gonna take?
把什麼治好？ 治我的病呀
-To do what? -The fixing. To fix me.
可能要比我想的費時一些
It's going to take a bit longer than I thought.
好的，得需要多久
Okay, that's fine. How long do you need?
3年
Three years.
對不起，能說清楚點嗎
Sorry, just go slowly with the clicks there,
你說的「3年」聽起來想是地球上的3年
it sounded like you said "three years", like human years.
是的，三年
Yes. Three years.
什麼？他媽的3年？
What? Three fuckin' years?
我會治好你的
I will fix you,
但首先我得拯救我的同伴
but first I must save my people.
我們的約定是：你能回家 我也能把病治好
The deal was: you go home, I get fixed!
我不會讓我的同胞淪為醫學實驗品的
I will not let my people be medical experiments!
我就是他媽的一個醫學實驗品 聽到我說的了嗎？ 克裡斯多夫？
I'm a fokkin' medical experiment! You hear me, Christopher?
我就是他媽的一個醫學實驗品
I'm a fokkin' medical experiment, man!
我必須回家並搬些救兵過來
I must go home and get help.
我必須用盡所有的流體 才能迅速飛回去
I must use all the fluid to travel quickly.
那我就得呆在這個爛地方了，克裡斯多夫？ 我就得呆在這個鬼地方了
I'll just stay here, Christopher? I'll just stay here in this shack.
- 3年後我才能見到你？ - 我答應你，我會回來的
And I'll see you in three years time? -I will come back. I promise.
克裡斯多夫！
Christopher!
他媽的去哪了？
Where the fuck is he?
嘿，你把維庫斯藏在下面了？
Hey, you're hiding Wikus down there, my boy?
- 爸爸？ - 不，不要
-Father? -No, no, no.
你父親得呆在這裡把一些事情處理好
Your daddy needs to stay here to sort out a few things, alright?
我們得走了，不過我們會回來接他，好嗎？
We're gonna go. We're gonna come back and fetch him, okay?
放在這裡？放進去 放進去？
In here? -In there. -Goes in here?
你們是怎麼打開這玩意的，大蝦？
How the fuck do you open this, prawn?
爸爸
Father.
告訴我怎麼弄，你這個混蛋 你是不是想讓我弄死你？
Show me, you fucker. You want me to fuckin' kill you?
這就是你想要的麼，阿？
Is that what you fuckin' want, eh?
好了...這裡沒有按鈕
Right... there's no buttons.
開機
On!
激活？
Activate?
我老師只教過我
My teachers teach only:
一個大蝦，一顆子彈
One prawn, one bullet.
難以置信，我拿錢就是幹這事的
I can't believe I get paid to do this.
我愛看著你們大蝦死去
I love watching you prawns die.
我操
Fuck, man!
爸爸
Father!
出去！出去
Get out! Get out!
這簡直太奇異了
This is remarkable.
看起來有什麼東西正從地下升起
It looks like something is emerging from the ground.
肯定有什麼東西正從地面升起來
Something is definitely coming out of the ground.
好了...穩點
Okay... steady!
坐下，我沒空搭理你了
Go sit down, I can't play with ya now.
維庫斯叔叔正在開飛船
Uncle Wikus is flying.
一邊去，一邊去
Bug off. Bug off!
武器鎖定目標
Lock the weapon at target!
鎖定後開火
Fire when locked.
看起來飛船正朝領土的中央開去
It seems to be drifting towards the center of the territory.
我們已經鎖定他了 開火
We have a lock on him. -Fire!
導彈已經發射出去了... 導彈打中了飛船
Something is fired upon... it has been hit!
這是怎麼回事
What the fuck is that?
有一個引擎已經開始冒煙 飛船開始失去控制了
One of the engines is billowing smoke, it's out of control.
它墮落下來了，頭 要不要我叫些兄弟去幹死他們
It's going down, boss. Should I send the boys to fuck him up?
現在，飛船已經撞到了地上 重重一撞
Now... it hit the ground, the massive impact,
飛船已經停下來了
and it's come to a standstill.
我的兒子 我的兒子還在上面
My son! My son's in there!
閉嘴 把他帶進去
Shut the fuck up! Get this fucker inside.
我們出發了 快，快走
We're moving out. Come, let's go, let's go...
快走
Move!
我們正在向目標靠近 以拍到更清晰的飛船畫面
We're banking around now, trying to get a better view of the ship
飛船已經完全撞毀了 等著濃煙被清理掉
which is absolutely wrecked, waiting for some of the smoke to clear.
有個人被從飛船上帶了下來
Somebody has been brought out of the vehicle.
看起來像是個人類
It looks like a human being.
我們得到一個未經證實的 消息說他可能是
We are getting unconfirmed reports that this might be
維庫斯·范德默爾，是MNU的一個
Wikus Van De Merwe, a fugitive that has been on the run
潛逃了三天的犯人
from MNU for the past 3 days.
他們把他押上了車，並開走了
They are loading him into a vehicle now, and heading off.
暴露72小時後
72 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
怎麼回事？
What the fuck?
我們抓到他了，頭 把他帶過來
We caught him, boss. -Bring him to me.
過來！回去
Come on! Get back!
我操！
Oh, fuck!
總部，我方與敵方交火，需要援助 需要援助，快點
Control, we're taking enemy fire! We need support. Backup, now!
出來，出來
Fuck off! Fuck off, man!
把手拿開 媽的，離我遠點
Get you hands off me! Fuckin' get off me!
放開我
Get your fuckin' hands off me!
我難道沒有告訴過你... 我會回來找你的？
Didn't I tell you... that I'm gonna get you?
你到這裡，然後你拿著 本屬於我的東西走了
You came in here and you left with something that belongs to me.
去你媽的
Fuck you.
去你祖宗十八代
Fuck you all!
我告訴過你這一天會到來的
I told you that the day will come.
你卻帶著我的戰利品跑了
You've been running around with my prize.
我就想吃了你的手 變得和你一樣
All I want is to eat that hand and become like you.
不！吃我的手不管用...
No! It won't work...
一旦我擁有了那種力量 就沒人能夠阻止我
Once I have that power, no one will stop me.
風水輪流轉...現在到我了
It was your turn... now it's mine!
和MNU安全部隊對著干 這些武裝分子死定了
Fighting MNU security forces, this armed faction is doomed...
現在我要開吃了，我的朋友
Now I'm gonna eat, my friend.
我們剛得到消息說 外星設備已經被啟動了
We're getting reports claiming that the alien device is activating...
你看到那個在車裡的大蝦了，是嗎？
You see that prawn back in the Casper? -Yeah.
他對飛船的構造很瞭解
He knows what the fuck is up with that ship.
抓他出來，並使他開口 套出東西出來
Get that fucker out and get him talking, now.
三方部隊正在靠近尼日利亞據點
Three contractors are closing in on the nigerian compound, and...
過來，外星人
Come, alien!
你有什麼陰謀
What's your plan?
你們怎麼弄到的？
How are you doing it?
誰在開那個飛船
Who's moving that ship?
好，這相當聰明
All right, that's very clever.
等我命令 確保一槍斃命
Wait for my command. Make sure you fuckin' shoot to kill.
操！快走！快走！
Fuck! Move it! Move it!
把那東西幹掉
Bring that fucker down!
停火！停火！ 原地別動
Hold you fire! Hold your fire and keep your positions!
他是范德默爾
It's Van De Merwe.
嘿，混蛋
Hey, Dickus!
我回來救那外星人的 是嗎？
I'll come back for prawn, alright guys?
聽到沒？ 快跑呀，維庫斯
Do you hear me, now? -Run, Wikus!
聽到我說的沒？ 快跑呀
-You hear me? -Run!
繼續跑呀 你這個膽小鬼
And keep on running, you fuckin' coward!
快跑，快跑
Run! Run!
請求空中支援 跟蹤他
Get the air support up, and get on his fuckin' trail, now!
不起作用，頭 他嘴硬得很
It's not gonna work, boss. He's a tough one.
他根本不透露任何消息 那直接斃了他
He's not gonna talk. -Then just fuckin' kill him.
操
Fuck!
他嘴很硬 不肯透露消息
He's a tough one. He's not gonna talk.
那就直接斃了他
Then just fuckin' kill him.
嘿，過來，起來 我要帶你離開這
Hey, c'mon. Get up! I'm gonna get you out of here.
我不行了...太遠了 不遠，快起來
-I can't... it's too far. -It's not too fokkin' far. Get up!
我會帶你過去 我要把你帶到你兒子身邊
I'm gonna get you there. I'm gonna get you to your boy!
來吧，跟我我身後
C'mon, stay behind me!
後退
Go back!
快跑，快跑，快跑
Run, run, run!
現在到達目地的了 我們得清除障礙
Arriving at the location now. We have a clearance to engage.
外星人過來了 趴下，趴下
Prawns are coming, get down, get down!
他們在朝降落點過去了 殺了這些混蛋
There are headed for a drop site. Knock these fuckers off!
來吧，來吧...
Come to mommy, come...
操
Fuck!
糟糕
Shit!
你受傷了？
Are you hurt?
我們可以做到 我手臂中彈了
We can make it. I was shot in the arm.
我們可以做到 快點
We can make it, come on!
聽著，你直走 你可以做到的
Listen, you go ahead. You can make it.
我來拖住他們 我待會再和你會合
I'm gonna just... hold them off here, and I'll join you soon.
不，我們要並肩作戰 我不會丟下你的
No, we stick together. I'm not leaving you here.
帶著你的孩子回家 你得做到
Take your boy and go home. You have to make it.
別讓我的辛苦白費了
Don't make me go through all of this and not make it.
你明白嗎？ 我會回來找你的
Do you understand? -I will come back for you.
趕緊！在我改變主意前 快走
Go! Go now before I change my mind! Go!
3年，我答應過你
Three years. I promise.
我他媽一點都不怕你們
I'm not fuckin' scared of you!
朝我開槍呀
Quit fuckin' with me!
想抓住我？ 想抓住我？
You want me? You want me?
這就是你那點本事嗎？
Is that all you got?
你他媽就那點本事嗎？
Is that all you fuckin' got?
從主飛船上發來一束 強烈的光線
Some kind of quite extraordinary light from the mothership.
我從來沒有見過任何類似的東西 它像一道光束
I've never seen anything like it. It's a beam of light...
全面掃瞄，好的
Full scan. Okay.
開火
Fire!
- 把那車開過來，快點 - 好的，上校   -快點快點
-Get to the vehicle, now! Get going. -Yes colonel. -Go, go, go!
操
Fuck!
不敢和我玩了，Koobus！
Quit playing with me, Koobus!
你這個混蛋
You fucker!
快走，克裡斯，走
Go, Chris, go.
回家
Go home.
我們現在回家了？
We go home now?
是的
Yes.
暴露74小時後
74 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
簡直難以置信
Unbelievable.
現在我知道為什麼人人都 想分一杯羹了
Now I know why everybody wants a piece of you.
我都迫不及待想讓醫生 解剖你了
I can't wait for those med boys to cut you up.
但你知道嘛？
But you know what?
我不會再讓你浪費我的一分一秒了
You're not gonna waste any more of my time.
你這個半獸人
You half-breed piece of shit!
我要親手宰了你
I'm gonna just fuckin' kill you myself.
退後，你他媽的 退後
Stay back, you fuck! Stay back!
退後
Stay back!
約翰內斯堡的所有人
The people everywhere across Johannesburg
都衝出了辦公室，涌向街頭
are flooding the streets and pouring out of their offices
所有的眼睛都在注視著這個重大的場面
and all eyes are pointed up towards the sky on this momentous day.
這是20年來，飛船首次
It's the first time, ladies and gentlemen, in over two decades,
向大家展示移動的痕跡
that the mothership has shown any sign of movement,
人群極度沸騰
and people are tremendously excited.
整座城市都凝固了
The city had come to an absolute standstill.
大家都想知道接下來會發生什麼
Everybody wants to know what's going to happen next.
究竟 克裡斯多夫·約翰遜會不會回來 已經無從考證了
There's no way of knowing whether or not Christopher Johnson will return.
不知道他是不是逃亡了
We don't know if he was simply escaping,
或者他在實施一個營救計劃
whether he will effect a rescue plan...
或者，會不會像媒體所言
...and, as the so called free press says,
會不會回來，向我們宣戰
whether or not he will come back and declare a war on us.
這是維庫斯·范德默爾 最後的影像記錄
This is the last known footage of Wikus Van De Merwe.
他究竟發生了什麼 我們只能猜測了
And we can only speculate as to what has happened to him.
一種陰謀論的理論是這樣解釋的
The more zany conspiracy theories state that
他已經被MNU或他國政府
he's been captured by MNU or by another government.
或者是政府特工逮捕了
Or by perhaps some shady government agency
已經被囚禁了起來
and he's actually being held in captivity.
如果我們知道他在哪裡？ 我們會試圖幫助他
If we knew where he was, we would try and help him,
而這才是難點所在，我們不知道 他身處何方
and that is the most difficult part, not knowing where he is.
維庫斯，很不幸的是，已經離開了 把所有的問題
Wikus, sadly, is gone but I'm the one who stays behind
留給了我一個人 而我卻無法回答
with all the questions. I can't give the answers.
在我心裡，他早已去了 僅此而已
He died in my mind a long time ago. And that's that.
維庫斯·范德默爾這個名字已經 是家喻戶曉了
Wikus Van Der Merwe is a name that will become very widely known
因為他在整個事件中 扮演了關鍵的角色
because of this pivotal role that he played in this whole event.
他是一個誠實的人 他不應該承受這一切
He was an honest man, and he didn't deserve any of what happened to him.
我是說，我進入了一個電腦系統 並發現了一些事實
I mean, I know. I looked into a computer system and I found stuff.
我的意思是所有的數據 都在裡面
I mean, the whole data was there, you know?
他們連藏都 沒藏好這些數據
They didn't even do a good job of hiding it.
方德斯瓦·莫拉嘎正在候審
Fundiswa Mhlanga is currently awaiting trial
由於曝光了MNU的非法基因研究項目
for exposing MNU's illegal genetic research program.
在外星人重安居計劃完成後
District 9 was demolished
第九區已經被拆毀了
after the alien resettlement operation was completed.
第十區現在容納有250萬外星人 而且數目仍在增長...
District 10 now houses 2.5 million aliens and continues to grow...
你們還沒見過我老婆的照片吧 給你們看看吧
You guys haven't seen a picture of my wife. Let me show you my wife.
她是我的天使
She's my special angel.
穿上婚紗，她看起來簡直就像是天使 你們想看看嗎？
She even looks like an angel with veil, you want to see that?
看，白色的婚紗...
Look, you see, with the white veil over the...
她看起來就像是天使 所有人都說我的老婆是天使
she even looks like an angel. Everyone says that his wife is angel,
這就是你透過鏡頭看到的 真正的天使
but this is a real angel that you see there, on the cameras.
他們不會把這個也播出去吧 應該不會
They won't put that in the video, I don't think.
我在門前發現了這個
I found this at my front door.
一定是某個人留下的
As tho somebody had just left it there.
我的朋友們說 我應該把這個扔掉
My friends say that I should throw it away,
因為它只是一片廢物
cause it's just a piece of rubbish.
可能是他送給我的 這好像很荒謬
That it couldn't possibly come from him.
但我相信這是真的
I know it's true.